Isaac Olanrewaju

Software Engineer

Address: 24, Dalberto Road, Palmgrove Estate, Ilupeju, Lagos State, Nigeria. Phone: +2348034240322

Email: <u>isaacolanre@gmail.com</u>
Github: <u>github.com/isaaclanre</u>

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/isaacolanrewaju/ Website: about.me/isaacolanre

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A computer science graduate with experience managing all aspects of the software development process. A specialist in the development of full-stack enterprise applications using agile methodologies. Always looking forward to new challenges in an agile workspace.

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Lagos — Software Engineer

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- A member of a team that developed an application that converts phone airtime to cash.
- Built useable react components and styled them with CSS.
- Wrote unit and integration tests to achieve 100% coverage.
- Led a small team in the development of an application that assesses software developers' readiness for technical assessments.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.

University of Abuja, Abuja — Software Developer

AUGUST 2019 - MAY 2022

- A member of a team that developed a Library Management application.
- Built projects with Nodejs, React.js, and Javascript.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.
- Improved the overall speed of the Library Management application by up to 40%.

Centre of Excellence for Sickle Cell Disease Research and Training,

Abuja — Assistant Database Manager (Part-time)

JULY 2017 - NOV 2021

- Designed database instruments that enrolled over 6000 sickle cell patients in four years.
- Automated recurring reports.
- Performed data analysis on over 6000 data sets.
- Trained over 30 data entry clerks in data management and analytics.

TECHNOLOGIES

- Nodejs
- Express
- Typescript
- Javascript
- React
- Redux
- Sequelize
- MySQL
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Docker
- HTML/CSS
- Git and GitHub
- TDD
- Postman
- Swagger

LANGUAGES

English

University of Abuja, Abuja — System Analyst

AUGUST 2015 - AUGUST 2019

- Managed a process that restructured communication flow among 8 departments and cut down paperwork by 75%.
- Recommended computer products and applications to improve productivity.
- · Conducted computer technology training with all new staff.
- Installed and maintained the University's computer systems and network.
- Provided technical assistance to staff and students.

Gwagwalada Area Council, Abuja — IT Support Technician

MARCH 2014 - FEBRUARY 2015

- Worked directly with the Planning, Research and Statistics Head of Department in updating staff records.
- Assisted office staff by providing solutions to computer application issues.
- Installed and configured software and hardware.
- Completed troubleshooting and repair when computers had problems.

PROJECTS

Airtime-to-Cash:

With Airtime-to-Cash, users can conveniently convert excess airtime to cash and withdraw this cash from their local banks.

Technologies Used - Node, Express, React, Typescript, SQL Database

Link: https://podfairtime2cash.netlify.app/

Job Ready App:

Using the Job Ready App, software engineers can be assessed on how prepared they are for technical assessments with a detailed report generated to help them know the areas they need to improve on.

Technologies Used - Express, React, Typescript, Sqlite3, Javascript, Express

Link: https://github.com/isaaclanre/job_ready_app.git

EDUCATION

Babcock University, Ogun State, Nigeria — B.Sc.

AUGUST 2008 - JUNE 2013

Computer Science (Informations Systems)